# Marlene

# **Summary**

SAP® FICO Consultant known for excellent problem-solving skills and leadership in the completion of business-critical projects. SAP® Implementation & Support career spans almost 15 years of experience in fast-paced retail, financing, SCM, and manufacturing industries. Proficient in SAP® B1, R3, and S4 HANA.

# **Experience**



### IT Consultant-SAP FICO

#### Continental

Jan 2020 - Present (3 years 8 months)

- Manages SAP FICO rollout projects for global clients: interaction with client key users and end-users, requirement gathering, functional specification, system configuration and testing, data migration, and user training.
- Collaborates with Project Management to gain a complete understanding of specific goals, objectives, and stakeholders.
- Expertise in data migration uploads via LSMW and/or Batch Input using BDC.
- Implements host-to-host (H2H) banking integrations
- Implements and supports integrations with other SAP modules such as GL, AA, AR, AP, MM, SD, TRM, HCM and Concur.
- Supports key users in case of questions during Integration Test and Hypercare.
- Analysis and resolution of bugs reported by the business during Integration tests and Hypercare.
- Interacts with onshore and offshore team members for any specific development needs.
- Establishes and maintains client relationships with a customer service perspective.

# IT-SAP FICO Officer

Robinsons Retail Holdings Inc.

Dec 2015 - Jan 2020 (4 years 2 months)

- Handled more than 12 full cycle implementations of SAP FICO for SAP ECC.
- Handled FICO configurations and managed change requests.
- Managed post go-live supports and issue logs.
- Conducted scoping, data gathering, blueprinting, and GAPS analysis from the business.
- Facilitated System Internal testing (SIT), User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and End User Training (EUT).
- Secured sign-off and approval documentation from the business.
- Prepared Functional Specifications, Configuration Documents, Unit Testing, Test Scripts, and User Manual documentation.
- Collaborated with developers and documented changes on ABAP-related requests.
- Handled integration issues with other SAP modules or other third-party/non-SAP systems.
- Prepared transport requests going to SAP Production for any change.
- Investigated and handled last-level support.
- Mentored junior team members.

- Ensured that all deliverables are provided to business on target.
- Assumed expanded responsibilities as interim Team Manager as needed.

# ERP Systems Specialist, Systems Implementation & Support Supervisor

Unistar Credit and Finance Corporation

May 2007 - Oct 2014 (7 years 6 months)

- Handled SAP MM & FICO configurations and approved user authorizations.
- Handled SAP A1 Master Data updates to GL accounts, Customers (AR) and Vendors (AP) accounts, Fixed Assets and House Banks (bank accounts setup).
- Handled SAP B1 GL Account Determination, Chart of Accounts (Segmented), Material Masters setup, Warehouses, Authorizations and other Master Data related setup.
- Requirements gathering for the development of Interface in SAP B1 (e.g. User Defined Fields or Formatted Search Queries).
- Trained users and colleagues on new ERP process implementations.
- Executed the closing and opening of Accounting Periods, Assets Fiscal Year and Materials Management (SAP MM) periods.
- Participated in the design of the integration process of SAP to banks' system interfaces.
- Participated in and supervised the testing process and documentation of test results.
- Reviewed documented user manuals used for formal user training.
- Served as Deep Support Analyst which investigates and resolves last-level support tickets.
- Conducted QA check of systems configuration and setups in development server prior to request of transport to production server.
- Designed and developed Functional Specifications document for Change Request to vendor.
- Proactively recommended enhancements to existing systems processes.
- Assumed expanded responsibilities as interim Team Manager as needed.



## Accounting Staff

Unistar Credit and Finance Corporation

Nov 2006 - Apr 2007 (6 months)

Responsibilities:

- Preparation of Financial Statement Report including Balance Sheet, Profit & Loss Statement and Cash Flow and other supporting reports.
- Reconciled Bank Balances versus per Book Balance.
- Performed different Fixed Asset transactions such as acquisition, depreciation, transfer, disposal and retirement.
- Handled validation and reconciliation of Notes Receivables data (including Gross Profit Rate, Promissory Note Amount, Cash on Discount/Delivery, etc.).
- Recorded retail branch's daily transaction in the system including disbursement, general journal entries, purchases & sales and collection report.
- Handled Petty Cash Fund Replenishment of assigned branches and prepared Liquidation Report.
- Recorded & monitored Journal Entries adjustments such as recurring entries, loan amortization, and bank interest/mortgages.
- Conducted actual physical count at branch level and make the necessary inventory adjustments in the system.



# Accounting/Billing Assistant

Star Music, ABS-CBN (former Star Records)

May 2006 - Nov 2006 (7 months)

- Responsible for the inventory report, sales report, and delivery monitoring.
- Handled the generation of billing statements for various record bar outlets.
- Handled monitoring of ending and beginning inventories and preparation of Inventory Count Sheet.
- Prepared Sales Invoice based on monthly inventory declared by promos and/or sales summary.
- Prepared Liquidation of Consignment Sales.
- Validated Delivery Receipts received from warehouse and monitored deliveries and sales on a monthly basis.
- Prepared Monthly Depreciation of Property Plant and Equipment.
- Assisted in Budgeting.

#### **Education**



## Divine Word College of Legazpi

Bachelor of Science - BS, Accounting Jun 2002 - Mar 2006

#### Skills

Financial Statements • Internal Financial Reporting • Accounting • Accounts Receivable (AR) • Financial Accounting • Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) • Journal Entries (Accounting) • Invoicing • A/R Collections • SAP ERP

#### **Honors & Awards**



Employee Of The Year 2022 - Continental Global Business Services (GBS) Manila Feb 2023

Includes multiple Employee of the Month Awards



The GBS Manila Award 2022 - Continental Global Business Services (GBS) Manila May 2023

In recognition of outstanding performance in the category \*Forward Thinking\*